Guide to the William H. Helfand Collection of Advertising Postcards, 1978-2000 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
William H. Helfand Collection of Advertising Postcards 1978-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Helfand, William H.
1.0 Linear Feet 534 Items
Collector and scholar of medical and pharmaceutical advertising, and advertising Go Cards.
Collection contains primarily advertising postcards (500 items, 1999-2000), mainly for clothing, entertainment, and alcoholic beverages, but also promoting AIDS awareness, AIDS drugs, and safe sex. The collection includes 5 handmade AIDS awareness cards from Burkina Faso; advertising cards for phone sex lines, 1978-1992; and 5 papers by Helfand on medical and pharmaceutical advertising. A copy of M. Rickard's ENCYCLOPEDIA OF EPHEMERA was removed from the collection and cataloged separately. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William H. Helfand Collection of Advertising Postcards were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001.
Collection Overview
Collection contains primarily advertising postcards (500 items, 1999-2000), mainly for clothing, entertainment, and alcoholic beverages, but also promoting AIDS awareness, AIDS drugs, and safe sex. The collection includes 5 handmade AIDS awareness cards from Burkina Faso; advertising cards for phone sex lines, 1978-1992; and 5 papers by Helfand on medical and pharmaceutical advertising. A copy of M. Rickard's ENCYCLOPEDIA OF EPHEMERA was removed from the collection and cataloged separately.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged by product or service type.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Helfand, William H.
Advertising
Advertising cards
Advertising -- Pharmaceutical industry
AIDS (Disease)
AIDS (Disease) -- Prevention
HIV (Viruses)
Safe Sex in AIDS prevention
Postcards
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Detailed Description of Collection
- Products and Services
  - Alcoholic beverages (Box 1)
  - American Express (Box 1)
  - Automobile (Box 1)
  - Barnes & Noble (Box 1)
  - Beauty products (Box 1)
  - Books (Box 1)
  - Business (Box 1)
  - Chewing gum and candy (Box 1)
  - Children (Box 1)
  - Cigarettes (Box 1)
  - Education (Box 1)
  - Express Worldbrand (Box 1)
  - Food and beverage (Box 1)
  - Forbes (Box 1)
  - Gyms and fitness (Box 1)
  - Internet/Phone services (Box 1)
  - Magazines (Box 1)
  - Mens' fashion (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Music (Box 1)
  - MTV (Box 1)
  - New York Times (Box 1)
  - Nonprofit/Aid organizations (Box 1)
  - Old Navy (Box 1)
  - Politics (Box 1)
  - Religion (Box 1)
  - Shopping (Box 1)
  - Silver Tab Levis (Box 1)
  - Sportswear (Box 1)
  - Technology/Electronics (Box 1)
  - Teeth/Dental Care (Box 1)
  - Television (Box 1)
  - Watches (Box 1)
  - Websites (Box 1)
  - Women's fashion (Box 1)
- Foreign/Travel
  - Amsterdam/Netherlands (Box 1)
  - Brussels/Belgium (Box 1)
  - Copenhagen/Denmark (Box 1)
  - France (Box 1)
  - Germany (Box 1)
  - International miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Italy (Box 1)
  - Spanish (Box 1)
  - Travel miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Health
  - Anti-drug abuse (Box 1)
  - Cancer (Box 1)
  - HIV/AIDS (Box 1)
  - OnHealth.com (Box 1)
  - Other (Box 1)
- Productions/Exhibits/Events
  - Art (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (Box 1)
  - Clubs/Night life (Box 1)
  - Comedy (Box 1)
  - Dance (Box 1)
  - Gay/Lesbian (Box 1)
  - Holiday (Box 1)
  - Movies and film (Box 1)
  - Museums (Box 1)
  - Music (Box 1)
  - Restaurants (Box 1)
  - Sports (Box 1)
  - Theater (Box 1)
- Large Format Items
  - AIDS, Aidens l'Afrique, handmade cards from Burkina Faso (Box 2)
  - HIV/AIDS (Box 2)
  - Phone sex/Adult entertainment (Box 2)
  - Various pamphlets
    - Clippings, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Learning from Medical Postcards, John Crellin and William Helfand, 1995 (Box 2)
    - The Pharmacy in Comic Postcards, W. Helfand and J. Crellin, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Pharmacy in History, John Crellin and William Helfand, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Vin Mariani, William Helfand, 1979 (Box 2)